DANIEL MARQUES

Gameplay Programmer | Informatics and Computing Engineer

PERSONAL

31/10/1997

Porto, Portugal

. +351 916 609 233

danfil.marques@gmail.com

github.com/rendoir

rendoir.github.io

PROFILE

Informatics and computing engineer, passionate about creating masterpiece games and giving memorable gaming experiences.

Enthusiastic and experienced in gameplay programming.

Knowledgeable and fascinated about computer graphics.

My goal in life is to be a part of the development of games that are appreciated as works of art. Games that live on in players' minds years after playing them. Games that perfectly balance a great narrative, engaging mechanics and immersive environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Gameplay Programmer

Ubisoft Québec

January 2022 - Present

Working on Assassin's Creed Codename Red.

Junior Gameplay Programmer

Ubisoft Berlin

August 2020 - January 2022

At Ubisoft Berlin, I worked on Far Cry 6 in the gameplay team. The game was at its closing stage when I joined and, consequently, my work on this project mainly consisted of bug and crash fixing and small features spanning the areas of gameplay ingredients, game mode logic, physics, weapons and gadgets, vehicles, player state, network replication, visual programming in quests and more.

I learned a lot during this time simply by virtue of being exposed to a large codebase and working with very knowledgeable people. Amongst the various self-improvements resulting from working at Ubisoft Berlin, I'd highlight my debugging skills, the ability to understand and navigate large codebases, my understanding of common implementations of some game systems, and teamwork and communication skills.

EDUCATION

Integrated Master's Degree Informatics and Computing Engineering

Faculty of Engineering University of Porto

2015 - 2020

Throughout this bachelor and master's degree, I studied mathematics, computer architecture, algorithms and data structures, computer graphics, object-oriented programming, software engineering, artificial intelligence, parallel computing, game development, virtual and augmented reality and much more. During this time, I also autonomously deepened my knowledge of C++ and game development.